<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Geoff&#39;s Life</title>
    <link>https://glw907.life/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Geoff&#39;s Life</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 14:29:39 -0900</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://glw907.life/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Declutter Diary: Day 8</title>
      <link>https://glw907.life/post/digital-declutter-diary-day-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 14:29:39 -0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://glw907.life/post/digital-declutter-diary-day-08/</guid>
      <description>One of the principles outlined in Digital Minimalism is the idea that you should use the time claimed by spending less time on digital distractions to pursue hobbies and leisure activities. I&amp;rsquo;ve certainly found quite a lot of new time, and I&amp;rsquo;m using some if it on this blog.
I&amp;rsquo;ve intentionally picked at &amp;ldquo;hand-on&amp;rdquo; tool for managing content. Specifically, I&amp;rsquo;m use the Hugo website development framework. It&amp;rsquo;s been a delight to use, and I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed flexing developer muscles that I haven&amp;rsquo;t used in years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Declutter Diary: Day 7</title>
      <link>https://glw907.life/post/digital-declutter-diary-day-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 16:08:55 -0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://glw907.life/post/digital-declutter-diary-day-07/</guid>
      <description>Wow &amp;hellip; I can&amp;rsquo;t believe that I&amp;rsquo;m one week in to the 30 day digital declutter already! The last couple of days have been super-busy. On Sunday I skied a 40k Tour of Anchorage cross-country ski race with my 13-year-old, and between prep, recovery, and coaching for Jr. Nordic on Saturday I didn&amp;rsquo;t find much time to write. And the last few days at work have been crazy.
I don&amp;rsquo;t really have a ton of time to write today either, but I did want to mention the fact that I&amp;rsquo;ve started to carry a weekly print edition of The Economist with me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Declutter Diary: Day 4</title>
      <link>https://glw907.life/post/digital-declutter-diary-day-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 11:22:50 -0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://glw907.life/post/digital-declutter-diary-day-04/</guid>
      <description>Not too much to report from the weekend. Per my original plan I didn&amp;rsquo;t carry a phone with me either Saturday or Sunday, although I did compromise by keeping keeping my personal mobile phone in the car all weekend. I think that this represented a pretty nice compromise.
On the one hand, spending time at restaurants, trails, ski races, coffee shops, etc. sans phone is remarkably nice. It definitely helps me be much more &amp;ldquo;present&amp;rdquo; and less distracted in my life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Declutter Diary: Day 3</title>
      <link>https://glw907.life/post/digital-declutter-diary-day-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 08:55:50 -0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://glw907.life/post/digital-declutter-diary-day-03/</guid>
      <description>So I&amp;rsquo;ve set up the Focus app on my laptop. I&amp;rsquo;m using this to block my access to the following sites:
 Google News Politico The New York Times The Economist The Anchorage Daily News FiveThirtyEight Reddit Apple Trailers KTUU  As a result, when I go to site on the above list I get to see a page that looks something like this, complete with a random and annoyingly earnest productivity quote:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Declutter Diary: Day 2</title>
      <link>https://glw907.life/post/digital-declutter-diary-day-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 17:11:34 -0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://glw907.life/post/digital-declutter-diary-day-02/</guid>
      <description>I have to admit that the FOMO-factor in this declutter experiment is higher than expected. I was thinking that because I&amp;rsquo;d already suffered through the pain of leaving social media many months ago that I&amp;rsquo;d have an easier time with this.
A significant percentage of my FOMO anxiety relates to texts. Today I processed all my texts twice as planned &amp;hellip; once about mid-morning and again before I finished up with work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Declutter Diary: Day 1</title>
      <link>https://glw907.life/post/digital-declutter-diary-day-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 15:14:00 -0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://glw907.life/post/digital-declutter-diary-day-01/</guid>
      <description>One of the initial challenges of this experiment is getting folks comfortable with my new communication regime. The fact that I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to stop (regularly) carrying a mobile phone outside of work hours has already caused some consternation at home. And my decision to maintain stricter separation between work and personal contact numbers and hours is prompting questions of &amp;ldquo;how do I know which number to use when I call or text you?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>30-Day Digital Declutter</title>
      <link>https://glw907.life/post/30-day-digital-declutter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 22:54:48 -0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://glw907.life/post/30-day-digital-declutter/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m just about to embark on the &amp;ldquo;Digital Declutter&amp;rdquo; exercise detailed in Digital Minimalism: Choosing a Focused Life in a Noisy World by Cal Newport. The process includes three steps:
Step one is putting aside a thirty-day period during which I will take a break from all optional technologies. That starts today!
Step two is exploring and reengaging in non-digital activities and behaviors that I find particularly satisfying and meaningful. I&amp;rsquo;m honestly pretty excited about this part of the exercise.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>